<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: aux | Ruby on Rails Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://hlee.github.com/blog/categories/aux/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://hlee.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-20T09:01:14-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://hlee.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ken Lu, Andrew Sheelan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working with Processes in Unix]]></title>
    <link href="http://hlee.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/working-with-processes-in-unix/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T07:08:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://hlee.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/working-with-processes-in-unix</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are two commands heavily used by developers for checking their pocesses
in unix.</p>

<ol>
<li>Firstly it is the search for processes</li>
</ol>


<p><code>sh
ps -ef | grep search_process
</code></p>

<p>or</p>

<p><code>sh
ps aux | grep search_process
</code></p>

<p>what's the difference, well both do the same task</p>

<p><a href="http://askubuntu.com/questions/129962/ps-ef-vs-ps-aux">link</a></p>

<p>Both list all processes of all users. In that aspect -e and ax are completely equivalent.
Where they differ is output format specifier, -f is "full", while u is "user-oriented". The displayed columns are different:
columns for ps -f
UID PID PPID C STIME TTY TIME CMD</p>

<p>columns for ps u
USER PID %CPU %MEM VSZ RSS TTY STAT START TIME COMMAND</p>

<p>The difference between ps -ef and ps aux is due to historical divergences between POSIX and BSD systems.
At the beginning, POSIX accepted the -ef while the BSD accepted only the aux form.</p>

<ol>
<li>Secondly to kill the process that we just found</li>
</ol>


<p><code>sh
kill -9 pid
</code></p>

<p>or</p>

<p><code>sh
kill -SIGKILL PID
</code></p>

<p>or if we know the process name and if the unix system supports</p>

<p><code>sh
killall nginx
</code></p>

<p>Tip: What if we need to kill all the processes that starts with 'schedule'.
Here it is..</p>

<p><code>sh
ps aux | grep schedule | grep -v grep | awk '{print $2}' | xargs kill -9
</code></p>

<p>A quick description of the steps:</p>

<ol>
<li>"ps aux | grep schedule" searches for the processes by the name schedule and
returns the rows</li>
<li>"grep -v grep" excludes grep from the searched process list (rows)</li>
<li>"awk '{print $2}'" prints the second column of all the values returned.
Which is mostly the process Id, if not choose the corresponding column by
its number of appearance in the rows returned</li>
<li>"xargs kill -9" sends the kill signal to all the selected process Ids</li>
</ol>


<p>Please make sure that you are searching for the right processes before killing them.</p>

<p>Any questions on this, please feel free to ask. We're here to help...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
